<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>completed | Temur Gugushvili</title>
    <link>/tag/completed/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tag/completed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>completed</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Temur Gugushvili 2020 - 2020 </copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/media/Mountain.png</url>
      <title>completed</title>
      <link>/tag/completed/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transformation of Livelihood Practices in Rural and Mountainous Settlements Located at the Edge of Protected Areas in Georgia (2018-2019)</title>
      <link>/project/livelihood_pa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/livelihood_pa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Now that significant inroads are made in the development of protected areas globally, Georgia as a country with transition economy joins this international movement, through its natural resource-rich mountainous areas along with celebrated wildlife and majestic beauty. In best words, Georgia faced rapid development of protected areas and their coverage in short stretch of times near urbanized territories in remote and mountain areas; therefore, this fact through ambivalent peculiarities of protected areas calls into question the resilience of locals in the process of adaptation of sustainable livelihood related to direct/indirect tourism-based activities. Out of the denoted nature, the research aims to delve into the process of how global phenomenon, namely expansion of tourism and protected areas shape livelihood practices of local mountain residents. Importantly, the study will shed the light of the ongoing transformation pathways of the society in transition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In such terms, to address the described phenomenon, the presented research applies rural sustainable livelihood concept  and as its objectives explores the following aspects of adaptation of tourism livelihood strategies: traditional livelihood practices of households; strategies and types of used capital to adapt new tourism sustainable and alternative livelihood practices; attitudes of indigenous mountain population towards PA establishment and advancement; formal and informal opportunities/limitations and their impact on the process of shaping adaptation process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The research project encompasses two case study PA&amp;rsquo;s and their surrounded areas:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://apa.gov.ge/en/protected-areas/cattestone/lagodexis-daculi-teritoriebis-administracia&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Lagodekhi Protected Area&lt;/a&gt;: (24,451 hectares) - one of the world’s best-preserved, primitive area with diversity of natural landscapes, located in the extreme north-eastern part of the southern slopes of the Caucasus and extends at an altitude of 590-3500 m;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://apa.gov.ge/en/eco-tourism/servisebi-da-tarifebi/machaxelas-erovnuli-parki&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Machakhela National Park&lt;/a&gt;: (7,359.44 hectares) located in the utmost south-west of Georgia in largely mountainous region, Adjara at an altitude of. 300-350 meters above Sea level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Principal Investigator: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=KP-aQeYAAAAJ&amp;amp;hl=en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gvantsa Salukvadze&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, PhD Candidate in Human Geography &lt;br&gt;
Co-Investigator: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=XIuUIMwAAAAJ&amp;amp;hl=en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Temur Gugushvili&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, PhD Candidate in Sociology&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Research Project is funded by Tbilisi State University and supported by the University of Hasselt (Belgium), Field Research Center for Environmental Sciences.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linkages Between Tourism and Community - Driven Economic Activities - Shaping Sustainability in Mountain Regions (2018-2020)</title>
      <link>/project/linkages_tourism/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/linkages_tourism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The interdisciplinary research project generally intends to unfold the possible scenario/model how the tourism development can promote socioeconomic improvement in mountainous regions of Georgia. With this in mind, the project serves primary aim to study the spatial peculiarities and barriers/obstacles of integration process of local community-driven economic activities with local tourism supply chain to promote the establishment of relevant linkages and synchronized development of economic fields in the mountain regions of Georgia. Admittedly, as the study generally seeks to bolster sustainable and inclusive tourism development, great emphasis will be placed on using community-based participatory approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The research project idea and the need of its implementation is inspired and derived from the research results of international interdisciplinary project &amp;ldquo;AMIES II - “Scenario Development for Sustainable Land Use in the Greater Caucasus, Georgia” funded by Volkswagen foundation. Based on the joint collaboration between the German (Justus Liebig University Giessen) and Georgian Universities (Tbilisi‐ based State Universities (ISU, TSU, AUG). AMIES II was conducted in one of the most visited resort places in mountain regions of Georgia- Kazbegu District (Municipality). As the research revealed, the rapid expansion of tourist sector (hotels and other accommodation, food joints, etc.) in the areas under investigation triggers notable economic progress, albeit the development is still fragmented and incomplete. Hence, this fact alludes to the inevitable need for thorough study of this phenomenon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research Areas: Kazbegi District/highland townlet; Mestia District/highland townlet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Principal Investigator - 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=knUVF8sAAAAJ&amp;amp;hl=en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prof. Dr. Joseph Salukvadze&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br&gt;
Project Coordinator - 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=XIuUIMwAAAAJ&amp;amp;hl=en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Temur Gugushvili&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, PhD Candidate &lt;br&gt;
Young Scientist - 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=KP-aQeYAAAAJ&amp;amp;hl=en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gvantsa Salukvadze&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, PhD Candidate&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Applicant Institution: Ivane Javakhishvili Tbilisi State University (TSU)
Partner Institution: Justus Liebig University Giessen
Foreign Research Consultant: Prof. em. Dr. I.-U. Leonhäuser&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consultants (TSU):&lt;br&gt;
Prof. Dr. Nino Pavliashvili (Department of Human Geography); &lt;br&gt;
Prof. Dr. Joseph Khelashvili (Department of Tourism and Hospitality Management); &lt;br&gt;
Prof. Dr. Nino Durglishvili (Department of Sociology),&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project is generously funded by 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://rustaveli.org.ge/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Shota Rustaveli National Science Foundation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
